# LU SHENG 盛律

Associate Professor @ Beihang University

College of Software, Beihang University No. 37, Xueyuan Road, Haidian District, Beijing, China ⊠ Isheng@buaa.edu.cn

☐ https://lucassheng.github.io/

# **Short Bio**

Dr. Lu Sheng is an **Associate Professor** (since 2019) at the College of Software in Beihang University (BUAA), Beijing, China. Previously, he was a postdoctoral researcher (2017-2019) in **MMLab@CUHK**, with **Prof. Xiaogang Wang**.

He received his Ph.D. (2011-2016) at the Department of Electronic Engineering in the Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), advised by **Prof. King Ngi Ngan**. He also has an internship (2015-2016) in Nanyang Technological University (NTU), with **Prof. Jianfei Cai**.

## Research Interests

His research interests include Computer Vision, Machine Learning and Multimedia, aiming at endowing machines with the capability to *perceive*, *understand*, *reconstruct*, and *interact* with the **3D visual world**, with the following focuses recently:

o Data-driven models for extracting hierarchical 3D semantics, inferring semantical/geometrical relationships, and rendering high-fidelity 2D/3D contents, based on multi-modal signals (including 2D/3D vision, language, etc) and beyond.

# Experience

- 2019-current Associate Professor, College of Software, Beihang University, Beijing, China.
  - 2016–2019 **Postdoctoral Researcher**, Image and Video Processing Laboratory, Department of Electronic Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.
    - o Topic: Deep Learning Driven Low-level and Middle-level Computer Vision
    - o Supervisor: Prof. Xiaogang Wang
  - 2015–2016 Visiting Research Assistant, BeingThere Centre, Institute for Media Innovation, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore.
    - o Topic: Real-time Depth-based Unconstrained Facial Pose and Expression Tracking in the Wild
    - o Supervisor: Prof. Jianfei Cai

## Education

- 2011–2016 Mphil-Ph.D Degree, Image and Video Processing Laboratory, Department of Electronic Engineering, the Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.
  - o Topic: RGB-D Video Processing Enhancement and Applications
  - o Supervisor: Prof. King Ngi Ngan
- 2007–2011 **B.E. Degree**, Department of Information Science and Electronic Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.

#### **Publications**

\* indicates equal contributions # indicates the corresponding author

#### **JOURNALS**

- [J-9] R. Su, D. Xu, L. Sheng, Wanli Ouyang, "PCG-TAL: Progressive Cross-granularity Cooperation for Temporal Action Localization", in IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), vol.30, pp.2103-2113, Dec. 2020.
- [J-8] C. H. Cheung, L. Sheng, K. N. Ngan, "Motion Compensated Virtual View Synthesis Using Novel Particle Cell", in IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM), vol.23, pp.1908-1923, June 2020.

- [J-7] L. Sheng\*, J. Pan\*, J. Guo, J. Shao, C.-C. Loy, "High-quality Video Generation from Static Structural Annotations", in International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV), vol.128, pp.2552-2569, May 2020.
- [J-6] L. Sheng, J. Cai, T-J. Cham, V. Pavlovic, K. N. Ngan, "Visibility-constrained Generative Model for Robust 3D Facial Pose Tracking", in *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence* (TPAMI), vol.41, no.8, pp.1994-2007, Aug. 2019.
- [J-5] B. Dong, L. Sheng, "Bags of Tricks for Learning Depth and Camera Motion from Monocular Videos", Virtual Reality & Intelligent Hardware (VRIH), vol.1, no.5, pp.500-510, 2019.
- [J-4] F. Wu, S. Li, T. Zhao, K. N. Ngan, L. Sheng, "Cascaded Regression using Landmark Displacement for 3D Face Reconstruction", in Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL), vol.125, pp.766-772, 2019.
- [J-3] C. H. Cheung, K. N. Ngan, L. Sheng, "Spatio-Temporal Disocclusion Filling Using Novel Sprite Cells", in IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM), vol.20, no.6, pp.1376-1391, Nov. 2017.
- [J-2] S. Li, K. N. Ngan, R. Paramesran and L. Sheng, "Real-time Head Pose Tracking with Online Face Template Reconstruction", in IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), vol.38, no.9, pp.1922-1928, Sept. 2016.
- [J-1] L. Sheng, K. N. Ngan, C-L. Lim and S. Li, "Online Temporally Consistent Indoor Depth Video Enhancement via Static Structure", in IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), vol.24, no.7, pp.2197-2211, July 2015.

#### Conferences

- [C-29] G. Liu, Y. Rong, L. Sheng#, "VoteHMR: Occlusion-Aware Voting Network for Robust 3D Human Mesh Recovery from Partial Point Clouds", in ACM Multimedia (ACM MM), Oral Presentation, 2021.
- [C-28] X. Wu\*, Z. Hu\*, L. Sheng#, D. Xu, "StyleFormer: Real-time Arbitrary Style Transfer via Parametric Style Composition", in IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021.
- [C-27] L. Zhao\*, D. Cai\*, L. Sheng#, D. Xu, "3DVG-Transformer: Relation Modeling for Visual Grounding on Point Clouds", in IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021.
- [C-26] Y. He\*, B. Gan\*, S. Chen\*, Y. Zhou\*, G. Yin, L. Song, L. Sheng, J. Shao, Z. Liu, "ForgeryNet: A Versatile Benchmark for Comprehensive Forgery Analysis", in IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), Oral Presentation, 2021.
- [C-25] B. Cheng, L. Sheng#, S. Shi, M. Yang, D. Xu, "Back-tracing Representative Points for Voting-based 3D Object Detection in Point Clouds", in IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.
- [C-24] Y. Yang, L. Sheng#, X. Jiang, H. Wang, D. Xu, X. Cao, "IncreACO: Incrementally Learned Automatic Check-out with Photorealistic Exemplar Augmentation", in Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2021.
- [C-23] Y. Qian, G. Yin, **L. Sheng**#, Z. Chen, Jing Shao, "Thinking in Frequency: Face Forgery Detection by Mining Frequency-Aware Clues", in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020.
- [C-22] R. Guo, C. Lin, C. Li, K. Tian, M. Sun, L. Sheng#, J. Yan, "Powering One-Shot Topological NAS with Stabilized Share-Parameter Proxy", in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020.
- [C-21] M. Liu, L. Sheng, S. Yang, J. Shao, S.-M. Hu, "Morphing and Sampling Network for Dense Point Cloud Completion", in AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020.
- [C-20] L. Sheng, D. Xu, W. Ouyang, X. Wang, "Unsupervised Collaborative Learning of Keyframe Detection and Visual Odometry towards Monocular Deep SLAM", in IEEE International Conference in Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019.
- [C-19] C. Tang, L. Sheng, Z.-X. Zhang, X. Hu, "Improving Pedestrian Attribute Recognition with Weakly-Supervised Multi-scale Attribute-Specific Localization", in IEEE International Conference in Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019.
- [C-18] Z. Wang, X. Liu, H. Li, L. Sheng, J. Yan, X. Wang, J. Shao, "CAMP: Cross-modal Adaptive Message Passing for Text-image Retrieval", in IEEE International Conference in Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019.
- [C-17] G. Yin, B. Liu, **L. Sheng**<sup>#</sup>, N. Yu, X. Wang, J. Shao, "Semantics Disentangling for Text-to-Image Generation", in *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR), Oral Presentation, 2019.

- [C-16] G. Yin, L. Sheng, B. Liu, N. Yu, X. Wang, J. Shao, "Context and Attribute Grounded Dense Captioning", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019.
- [C-15] J. Pan, C. Wang, X. Jia, J. Shao, L. Sheng#, J. Yan, X. Wang, "Video Generation from Single Semantic Label Map", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019.
- [C-14] B. Li, W. Ouyang, L. Sheng, X. Zeng, X. Wang, "GS3D: An Efficient 3D Object Detection Framework for Autonomous Driving", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019
- [C-13] Y. Liu, L. Sheng, J. Shao, J. Yan, S. Xiang, C. Pan, "Multi-Label Image Classification via Knowledge Distillation from Weakly-Supervised Detection", in ACM Multimedia (ACM MM), 2018.
- [C-12] G. Yin, L. Sheng, B. Liu, N. Yu, X. Wang, J. Shao, C-C. Loy, "Zoom-Net: Mining Deep Feature Interactions for Visual Relationship Recognition", in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2018.
- [C-11] L. Sheng, Z. Lin, J. Shao, X. Wang, "Avatar-Net: Multi-scale Zero-shot Style Transfer by Feature Decoration", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018.
- [C-10] Y. Liu\*, F. Wei\*, J. Shao\*, L. Sheng, J. Yan, X. Wang, "Exploring Disentangled Feature Representation Beyond Face Identification", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018.
- [C-9] S. Sun, Z. Kuang, L. Sheng, W. Ouyang, W. Zhang, "Optical Flow Guided Feature: A Fast and Robust Motion Representation for Video Action Recognition", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018.
- [C-8] X. Liu, H. Zhao, M. Tian, L. Sheng, J. Shao, S. Yi, J. Yan, X. Wang, "HydraPlus-Net: Attentive Deep Features For Pedestrain Analysis", in IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2017.
- [C-7] L. Sheng, J. Cai, T-J. Cham, V. Pavlovic, K. N. Ngan, "A Generative Model for Depth-based Robust 3D Facial Pose Tracking", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2017.
- [C-6] C. H. Cheung, L. Sheng and K. N. Ngan, "A disocclusion filling method using multiple sprites with depth for virtual view synthesis", in IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo Workshop (ICMEW), 2015.
- [C-5] L. Sheng, K. N. Ngan and T-W. Hui, "Accelerating the Distribution Estimation for the Weighted Median/Mode Filters", in Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2014.
- [C-4] L. Sheng, K. N. Ngan and S. Li, "Temporal Depth Video Enhancement Based On Intrinsic Static Structure", in IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), Oral Presentation, 2014.
- [C-3] S. Li, K. N. Ngan and L. Sheng, "Screen-camera Calibration Using a Thread", in IEEE International Conference On Image Processing (ICIP), 2014.
- [C-2] L. Sheng, K. N. Ngan and S. Li, "Depth Enhancement Based On Hybrid Geometric Hole Filling Strategy", in IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2013.
- [C-1] S. Li, K. N. Ngan and L. Sheng, "A Head Pose Tracking System Using RGB-D Camera", International Conference on Computer Vision Systems (ICVS), Oral Presentation, 2013.

#### **Professional Services**

- Executive Area Chair of Vision and Learning SEminar (VALSE), 2020, 2021.
- Technical Committee Member on 3D Vision, China Society of Image and Graphics (CSIG), 2021.
- o Senior Program Commitee (SPC) or Area Chair of
  - International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021, 2022
  - AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022
  - ACM Multimedia Asia, 2021
- o Journal reviewer of
  - IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (T-PAMI)
  - International Journal on Computer Vision (IJCV)
  - IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (T-IP)
  - IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (T-MM)
  - IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (T-CSVT)
  - and etc.
- Conference reviewer of
  - IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)
  - IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)
  - European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)
  - International Conference of Machine Learning (ICML)
  - AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)
  - Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)
  - International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)
  - and etc.
- Member: IEEE/CVF, AAAI, CCF/CSIG/CAAI and etc.